RG 125, Connecticut Peace Society
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Peace Society records
1910-1921
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Peace Society
1 cubic foot
The Connecticut Peace Society appears to have been established in 1910, “to foster the spirit of amity and concord among the nations, and to create a public sentiment which will lead to the abandonment of war as a means of settling international disputes.”
RG125
1921-037
Historical Note
The Connecticut Peace Society appears to have been established in 1910, “to foster the spirit of amity and concord among the nations, and to create a public sentiment which will lead to the abandonment of war as a means of settling international disputes.” It functioned as a division of the American Peace Society, holding annual meetings, sponsoring peace essay contests, distributing pamphlets and other printed materials, and expressing its views through the press and by communications with government officials. On April 1, 1921, it ceased independent existence, though the American Peace Society continued.
Scope and Content
The collection includes a constitution, contest essays, correspondence, financial records, and publications.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut Peace Society
Subjects:
Connecticut Peace Society -- Records and correspondence; Peace -- Societies, etc
Document Types:
Constitutions; Correspondence; Financial records; Essays; Resolutions (administrative records); Leaflets; Posters; Minutes
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
These papers came to the State Library in 1921, from Professor Curtis M. Geer, Secretary, and in 1944, from Mrs. Curtis M. Geer.
Container List
- Records, 1910-1921
  - 1. Minutes, 1914-1920; 1 volume (Box 1)
    Marked as volume 2.
  - 2. Constitution, 1910-1916; typescript with notations (Box 1)
    Signed by original members and modified in pencil in 1916.
  - 3. Correspondence, 1913-1921 (Box 1)
    Unarranged.
  - 4. Contest essays, 1913-1915 (Box 1)
    Essays on peace subjects and copies of contest rules.
  - 5. Ledger, 1912-1920; 1 volume (Box 1)
    Evidently the Secretary's account book, listing dues received and amounts turned over to the Treasurer.
  - 6. Accounting records, 1910-1921 (Box 1)
    - Cancelled checks, shared folder (Box 1)
    - Check stubs, shared folder (Box 1)
    - Deposit books, shared folder (Box 1)
    - Bank books, shared folder (Box 1)
    - Paid bills with related correspondence, 1 folder (Box 2)
  - 7. Publications, 1914-1917; 3 folders (Box 2)
    Copies of leaflets, posters, lists of published materials, etc., of other peace organizations in the United States and Europe.